<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>containers - Tag - INGE4PRES RATIONAL THOUGHTS</title>
        <link>https://inge.4pr.es/tags/containers/</link>
        <description>containers - Tag - INGE4PRES RATIONAL THOUGHTS</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 15:00:51 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inge.4pr.es/tags/containers/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Progressive Delivery with Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://inge.4pr.es/post/progressive-delivery-with-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 15:00:51 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>inge4pres</author>
    <guid>https://inge.4pr.es/post/progressive-delivery-with-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;m more and more fond of finding the perfect solution to manage application delivery: dev teams want to be fast but their ops counterpart is not happy to loose control over the growing number of deployments that could cause an outage. We as an industry need to find the right balance to have features delivered in time and keep the service up and running for our users! And that&rsquo;s where progressive delivery can help!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Continuous Delivery with Drone</title>
    <link>https://inge.4pr.es/post/continuous-delivery-with-drone/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 16:47:05 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>inge4pres</author>
    <guid>https://inge.4pr.es/post/continuous-delivery-with-drone/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Continuous Delivery should be a solved issue: the practice is well-defined and there is a plethora of tools implementing it with more or less peculiarities, but still many struggle implementing it. The dream of a perfect continuous deployment flow from the developer to the production environment with software quality gates based on automated tests is still alive in me, I tried and tried several times with multiple implementations on multiple platforms and never got to the point where I could say: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m done, this works exactly as I wanted&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
