<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inge4pres rational thoughts</title>
    <link>http://inge.4pr.es/</link>
    <description>Recent content on inge4pres rational thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 19:40:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://inge.4pr.es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Concurrency Patterns</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/10/28/2017-10-28-golang-concurrency-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 19:40:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/10/28/2017-10-28-golang-concurrency-pattern/</guid>
      <description>In the early days of Go the language was often tailored towards &amp;ldquo;system programming&amp;rdquo; due to its C-stlye syntax and ability to write high-performance applications. Few time after, Go adoption was starting to gain traction for distributed systems development and projects like etcd, docker and kubernetes revealed the power of the networking capabilities offered by the internals in the language. Along the way a lot of libraries have been built around the powerful primitives offered by Go but in my opinion there is not enough use literature around the Communicating Sequential Processes implementation available through channels and goroutines, they are not even widely used in the standard library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 15:27:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/resume/</guid>
      <description>Work experiences 9&amp;frasl;2017 - now() » DevOps Engineer @ lastminute.com I am contributing to the development of a CI/CD platform to enable developers to test and deploy code easily and with confidence; we collaborate with SRE team to provide automated services to consume infrastructure. The end-user platform runs on Kubernetes and we leverage Jenkins and Docker to shorten the feedback loop and aid the software improvement cycle from dev to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Google Cloud Builder</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/10/01/2017-10-01-getting-started-with-google-cloud-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 21:31:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/10/01/2017-10-01-getting-started-with-google-cloud-builder/</guid>
      <description>One of the advantages of containerized applications is the standardization, some would say &amp;ldquo;write it once, runs everywhere&amp;rdquo; but that&amp;rsquo;s another motto for another product. Anyway with a new packaging technology the same problems are faced: build reproducibility, or the necessity for people doing Ops to know they are going to deploy the same exact piece of code the Dev team used in their tests. So to address this issue the container image needs to be immutable: once it&amp;rsquo;s built, it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be changed, ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps: you&#39;re doing it wrong</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/05/28/2017-05-28-devops-you-re-doing-it-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 17:04:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2017/05/28/2017-05-28-devops-you-re-doing-it-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Recently I received a mail pointing me to a post about DevOps culture and some anti-patterns and misconception on how to build and grow a DevOps culture in a company. Whoever like me works in the Enterprise (&amp;ldquo;the one with the big E&amp;rdquo; - Kelsey Hightower) knows that applying DevOps practices often is limited to the adoption of some tools or the creation of a &amp;ldquo;DevOps team&amp;rdquo; responsible of managing some continuous delivery pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate TLS management on AWS with LetsEncrypt</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/12/03/2016-12-03-automate-tls-management-on-aws-with-letsencrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 15:34:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/12/03/2016-12-03-automate-tls-management-on-aws-with-letsencrypt/</guid>
      <description>Letsencrypt is cool: automated, free TLS certificates for everybody! They are sponsored mainly by internet corps and they started a crowd-funding campaign to avoid the influence of this corps in the future of the project. I recently moved the blog to hugo on AWS and I&amp;rsquo;m now porting the TLS management scripts I wrote a while ago on AWS: this is a nice exercise to give a proper TLS automation valid for everyone on AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4pres goes #serverless</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/11/17/2016-11-17-4pres-goes-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 18:28:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/11/17/2016-11-17-4pres-goes-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Last month I felt I was a little late for the #serverless party going on all over the internet and I started taking a look at what the pros and cons would be to actually not manage any server myself. Shutting down my VPS hosting my apps I will loose my mail server, my MySQL instances and my Docker registry but: who cares? There are cloud services I can use with hundreds of times more availability and for a fraction of the cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 15:27:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/about/</guid>
      <description>Bio I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate technology enthusiast, an engineer in love with Computer Science and a part-time musician and writer; I started my career in IT as a sysadmin and became a Go developer in 2013 when approaching distributed systems. I like to study how things work, understand the mechanics of technology products. In my spare time I play drums, bass guitar and acoustic guitar, and sometimes try and write some music; writing small poems is also a passion of mine, as it helps me find a different meaning to things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving the blog to hugo</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/10/10/2016-10-10-moving-the-blog-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 20:07:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/10/10/2016-10-10-moving-the-blog-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>In times of experimenting, I am now having a lot of fun with docker, rkt, kubernetes and containers ecosystem in general. But one thing I never forget to play with is content editing and publishing! So here I am, trying to migrate all my blog and website to Hugo :)
So instead of a bare VPS I am moving my blog to AWS S3 + Cloudfront CDN. This will be more scalable and far less expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A benchmark of AWS EFS</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/09/18/2016-09-18-a-benchmark-of-aws-efs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 17:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/09/18/2016-09-18-a-benchmark-of-aws-efs/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Services Elastic File System has been to my knowledge the service to have the longest beta testing period: reason for this may be that not as many client as expected tested it and AWS received too few feedback on it or that there were issues not to release GA. I don&amp;#8217;t want to speculate on which one is correct but now that it has been officially released I decided to give it a try and of course compare it to a self-managed solution on the same platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS IAM policy to let users manage their own MFA</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/04/06/2016-04-06-aws-iam-policy-to-let-users-manage-their-own-mfa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 19:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/04/06/2016-04-06-aws-iam-policy-to-let-users-manage-their-own-mfa/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;#8217;re an AWS administrator you know that managing web console security is pretty tough unless you know what you want and you know what you&amp;#8217;re doing. So if what you want is let each AWS user manage their own MFA device configuration without you and force them to have MFA active to use the web console, here is your solution.
TL;DR
 Create one or more groups with your web users Create a new policy using this JSON Attach the policy to the group(s)  How does it work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement a generic data list structure</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/01/24/2016-01-24-implement-a-generic-data-list-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 16:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/01/24/2016-01-24-implement-a-generic-data-list-structure/</guid>
      <description>As a coding challenge I was asked to provide a generic list implementation using a language of my choice and using only primitive types, avoiding the use of high level built-ins. I chose Go because I want to learn it and I know it can be useful to create an abstract, generic implementation.
The challenge request to implement at least 4 methods on the generic type:
 Filter() &amp;#8211; returns a subset of the List satisfying an operation Map() &amp;#8211; returns the List objects&amp;#8217; map Reverse() &amp;#8211; reverse the ordering of the List objects FoldLeft() &amp;#8211; join the objects from left to right using a join character  As a bonus question I was asked to code unit tests for the aforementioned methods and give an explanation on how the implementation guarantees concurrent access on resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualize an old Windows PC</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/01/24/2016-01-24-virtualize-an-old-windows-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 15:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2016/01/24/2016-01-24-virtualize-an-old-windows-pc/</guid>
      <description>A friend asked me if I was able to get back working a Windows 98 PC he had in his house; I have never done it so I said &amp;#8220;sure I can!&amp;#8221; just to have the opportunity to learn something new, and of course do a friend a favour.
My idea was to copy the whole PC and get it running on a virtual machine thus doing what I later discovered is called a &amp;#8220;P2V&amp;#8221; (Physical to Virtual); the result of which would have been a portable VM which I could then install in my friend laptop to have his old PC back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Message Queue: a simple TCP message bus</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/08/02/2015-08-02-golang-message-queue-a-simple-tcp-message-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 16:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/08/02/2015-08-02-golang-message-queue-a-simple-tcp-message-bus/</guid>
      <description>[TL;DR]
I wrote a Pub/Sub message queue in Go, branch &amp;#8220;master&amp;#8221; is stable but missing some interesting feature like distributed memory synchronization between nodes in a cluster and encryption. Code at
https://github.com/inge4pres/gmq
Being a cloud system engineer, my work is to design and implement distributed systems: one of the key principles in designing such architectures is decoupling, which means ensuring the many parts composing the system are able to share informations and complete a sequence of operations without being tied together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Golang web project is online</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/06/11/2015-06-11-my-first-golang-web-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/06/11/2015-06-11-my-first-golang-web-project/</guid>
      <description>It is true: I fell in love with Go, not because I love Google and his products, but because it really fits my ideology of simplicity and power in a programming language. I started experimenting with the language and thank to his web-oriented approach I quickly came up with one of the simplest single task web application I could write: a URL shortener.
What is a URL shortener? It&amp;#8217;s a service that will give you a short link for a long URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GlusterFS: is it suitable for me?</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/03/11/2015-03-11-glusterfs-is-it-suitable-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2015/03/11/2015-03-11-glusterfs-is-it-suitable-for-me/</guid>
      <description>During the last years I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with GlusterFS and his functionalities as distributed object store; a lot has changed in the software, overall since Red Hat acquired it. I have been using it and find it useful for many projects but not for others: what I love is the community oriented approach with a very responsive team and support for any kind of users (meaning from the 2 nodes web server to a RAID10 Infiniband cluster for high end storage).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a private master/slave DNS using BIND</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/12/19/2014-12-19-set-up-a-private-masterslave-dns-using-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 17:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/12/19/2014-12-19-set-up-a-private-masterslave-dns-using-bind/</guid>
      <description>One of the very basic need of any startup is setting up a LAN in the workspace and configuring the Internet most used service: DNS. Relying on a public DNS may give you full functionality towards WAN connectivity, but when you need to address some hosts inside your LAN it can be handy to use names instead of IPs (especially with IPv6).
Here&amp;#8217;s a straight forward guide to get you started with your private DNS in a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy birthday server!</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/12/11/2014-12-11-happy-birthday-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/12/11/2014-12-11-happy-birthday-server/</guid>
      <description>In an attempt to make someone happier I wrote a script to notify a server admin when his child has gone through a year of uptime 🙂
Platform suggestions accepted, enjoy!
happy_bday_server script</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A smooth migration to the cloud</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/10/15/2014-10-15-a-smooth-migration-to-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 18:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2014/10/15/2014-10-15-a-smooth-migration-to-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>The last weekend my colleagues and I had a nice time moving an existing application from a bare-metal infrastructure to AWS. I would like to share some of the focal points involved in such process, in case you&amp;#8217;d go through it and would like to know:
 don&amp;#8217;t expect everything to work as usual: you are changing the underlying hardware, moving to a virtualized environment. You can test every single part of the application but infrastructural side effects may occur in a second time relying on the provider: consider well which functionalities should be delegated to the cloud provider (AWS, in this case, offers a lot) or should be managed internally; for example S3 is not a distributed filesystem, and in some cases an RDS instance won&amp;#8217;t have the same performance as database installed on an EC2 instance test application compliance, not hardware failure: instead of focusing on stress tests, you should focus first on functionality tests to ensure every part of te application is behaving as expected; hardware failure are easily handled in the cloud, that&amp;#8217;s the primary purpose of IaaS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and restore crontabs</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/11/11/2013-11-11-backup-and-restore-crontabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 10:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/11/11/2013-11-11-backup-and-restore-crontabs/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s a thing I came up with: you&amp;#8217;re administering a Linux system with 100 users circa and you&amp;#8217;re moving to a new server, you can save crontabs per user with this:
mkdir crontabz &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd crontabz; for user in `cat /etc/cron.allow`; do crontab -l -u $user &amp;gt; cron_$user; done
you will end up with a list of files _cronxxx, each one has the users&amp;#8217; cron. Hopefully your cron version will use the /etc/cron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zabbix: a powerful yet simple monitoring software</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/10/07/2013-10-07-zabbix-a-powerful-yet-simple-monitoring-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 15:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/10/07/2013-10-07-zabbix-a-powerful-yet-simple-monitoring-software/</guid>
      <description>It may come in mind to any IT system engineer to know what is the status of the network, server by server, instance by instance; it happened to me when I was given the responsibility to manage my company&amp;#8217;s infrastructure and I was wondering which tool could have helped to do the job.
I chose Zabbix to monitor my infrastructure because:
 despite it&amp;#8217;s a bit difficult to install (you need a PHP enabled web server, a database and a C compiler), you will benefit a very user-friendly web interface with lots of functionalities native agents for major OS release are already complied: FreeBSD, Linux, Windows, etc&amp;#8230; Compiling to other OS just requires a &amp;#8220;configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install&amp;#8221; it offers many monitoring methods via a unique interface: you can group SNMP, JMX, HTTP monitoring in one shot it has multi-step HTTP/HTTPS monitoring, simulating different browsers and clients you can build nice infographics bundling all kind of monitored datas you can manage users and roles to give access to the web interface at your company&amp;#8217;s employees you can build custom monitoring scripts to your needs  Well let&amp;#8217;s see some action now: I would like to post a short tutorial on how to build a custom script to monitor resources used by a Glassfish application server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quando si dice problem solving</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/02/28/2013-02-28-quando-si-dice-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 20:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2013/02/28/2013-02-28-quando-si-dice-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>Ieri in ufficio mi è capitata una disgrazia, una rara occasione in cui non c&amp;#8217;è capacità o competenza che possano aiutarti a risolvere il caso, serve solo fortuna: nel pomeriggio rientro dalla sigaretta e mi sento dire &amp;#8220;non abbiamo più rete&amp;#8221;.
L&amp;#8217;azienda dove lavoro si occupa di fornire servizi IT, senza la connessione internet siamo un&amp;#8217;auto senza motore, una penna senza inchiostro, inutili.
La linea di backup?
All&amp;#8217;inizio incolpo subito il nostro ISP (Fastweb), che a discapito di una fibra 100Mb ci ha giocato in passato scherzi del genere; quando la verifica evidenzia che non è un loro problema, il panico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Mini: la musica dello spot TV</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/11/26/2012-11-26-ipad-mini-la-musica-dello-spot-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 16:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/11/26/2012-11-26-ipad-mini-la-musica-dello-spot-tv/</guid>
      <description>Ieri mi sono trovato con parte della mia famiglia nella loro sala a suonare un po&amp;#8217; il pianoforte, mio fratello Gianmaria e io ci siamo esibiti riproducendo la semplice (ma efficace) musica che accompagna la pubblicità dell&amp;#8217;iPad Mini.
Il motivetto è in Do maggiore così come viene proposto suonando i due iPad nella pubblicità, di seguito il video. Enjoy!
&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Università: facoltà di psicologia</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/10/05/2012-10-05-universita-facolta-di-psicologia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 16:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/10/05/2012-10-05-universita-facolta-di-psicologia/</guid>
      <description>In Italia abbiamo molti problemi, ma l&amp;#8217;ultimo dei nostri problemi era l&amp;#8217;istruzione che vantava uno dei primi posti al mondo fino a pochi anni fa. Ora invece il declino strutturale del nostro Paese ha colpito anche questo settore che era di valore. Parlo di mancanza di fondi per università e ricerca, di formazione non orientata al lavoro e tutto ciò che ne consegue: l&amp;#8217;aumento della disoccupazione giovanile e della sfiducia nel futuro è preoccupante perché è nella stesso ordine di grandezza di stati molto indietro rispetto alla media europea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Il significato della parola Islam</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/08/20/2012-08-20-ho-capito-il-significato-della-parola-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 17:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/08/20/2012-08-20-ho-capito-il-significato-della-parola-islam/</guid>
      <description>Stamattina ho lavorato all&amp;#8217;Arena Civica di Milano come tecnico del suono. La manifestazione che ho seguito era la cerimonia di chiusura del Ramadan islamico, l&amp;#8217;equivalente della Pasqua cristiana. La cerimonia di per sè è stata breve, circa un&amp;#8217;ora, ed è stato affascinante assistere a una manifestazione religiosa a cui non avevo mai assistito prima. Il programma è stato il seguente:
 raduno dei fedeli nel campo dell&amp;#8217;Arena presentazione dei celebranti del rito preghiera sermone sfollaggio  Innanzitutto ciò che mi ha colpito è stata la mole di persone che erano presenti: circa 15000 tra uomini donne e bambini; da notare che la religione islamica non conta solo fedeli dal medio oriente, gran parte infatti erano di origine africana e indonesiana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musica e linguaggio: un&#39;involuzione al passo coi tempi</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/30/2012-07-30-musica-e-linguaggio-uninvoluzione-al-passo-coi-tempi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 20:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/30/2012-07-30-musica-e-linguaggio-uninvoluzione-al-passo-coi-tempi/</guid>
      <description>Una cosa che adoro di questo millennio è l&amp;#8217;abbondanza di dati: nella storia l&amp;#8217;uomo ha sempre cercato di tramandare ai posteri la propria vita e io credo che i dati raccolti e archiviati dall&amp;#8217;umanità nel secolo scorso siano in valore di molte volte superiori a ogni calendario Maya o testo sacro. Trovo fantastica la sensazione che si prova guardando un pezzo comico di Valter Chiari di 50 anni fa e immedesimandomi nei miei genitori per esempio, che hanno assistito alle stesse scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discorsi economici finiti in un mashup!</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/10/2012-07-10-discorsi-economici-finiti-in-un-mashup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/10/2012-07-10-discorsi-economici-finiti-in-un-mashup/</guid>
      <description>Ed eccolo!!
Il mashup che stavate aspettando dopo la cena con più argomenti di economia della mia vita!
Impressionante&amp;#8230;
http://inge.4pr.es/files/2014/07/tranx-mashup.ogg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferro da stiro, mon amour&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/09/2012-07-09-ferro-da-stiro-che-passione/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 20:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/07/09/2012-07-09-ferro-da-stiro-che-passione/</guid>
      <description>Mio amato ferro da stiro, è da 4 mesi che ci conosciamo e il nostro rapporto è intenso e caloroso tanto quanto la tua piastra in acciaio Inox. Sei un compagno di molte sere in cui, poichè non ho proprio niente da fare, ti accendo e passiamo insieme momenti fantastici mentre lisci le pieghe dei miei vestiti&amp;#8230; Devo dire che era da molto che non avevo un rapporto così intenso e infatti, parafrasando la fantastica canzone di Marco Ferradini</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vivere le proprie passioni, con passione!</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/23/2012-05-23-vivere-le-proprie-passioni-con-passione/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 19:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/23/2012-05-23-vivere-le-proprie-passioni-con-passione/</guid>
      <description>Ho appena avuto la fortuna di fare un incontro, un incontro speciale di quelli che ti restano impressi per sempre. Non credo nel destino o fato o casualità che dir si voglia, seppure una serie di circostanze che hanno portato a questo incontro potrebbero farmi cambiare idea.
La storia è questa: da pochi mesi ho deciso di inziare con mio fratello Gianmaria la ristrutturazione di uno studio musicale. Lo studio è stato costruito da mio padre 25 anni fa ed era in disuso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;ennesima dimostrazione dello stato ladro!</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/22/2012-05-22-lennseima-dimostrazione-dello-stato-ladro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 20:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/22/2012-05-22-lennseima-dimostrazione-dello-stato-ladro/</guid>
      <description>Come dice Oscar Giannino, giornalista e conduttore radiofonico, nonchè grande conoscitore dei meccanismi dell&amp;rsquo;economia italiana, lo stato italiano invece di salvaguardare i propri cittadini, li deruba, li sfrutta, si prende gioco di loro; per utilizzare una frase del sempre impeccabile editorialista bisogna cercare di difendersi dallo &amp;#8220;Stato LADRO!!!&amp;#8221;.
La situazione dell&amp;#8217;economia italiana non è delle migliori, anzi, proprio oggi l&amp;#8217;ISTAT ha pubblicato un report che indica come il reddito pro capite è uguale a quello del 1992 e fatti estremi stanno accadendo sempre più numerosi giorno dopo giorno.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy e riservatezza: il digital divide</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/21/2012-05-21-privacy-e-riservatezza-il-digital-divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 17:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/21/2012-05-21-privacy-e-riservatezza-il-digital-divide/</guid>
      <description>Ho sempre vissuto in città di provincia (MI) dove è abitudine frequentare una cerchia ristretta di persone. Questo mi ha permesso di stringere legami molto forti con chi considero i miei amici, ma allo stesso tempo non mi ha favorito nello sviluppo di una sensibilità verso la gestione delle informazioni personali nella vita reale; la mia lingua lunga ha solo fatto piovere sul bagnato&amp;#8230;
 Il paese è piccolo e la gente mormora&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog RE-start</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/18/2012-05-18-blog-re-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/2012/05/18/2012-05-18-blog-re-start/</guid>
      <description>Il blog è tornato in vita dopo 24 ore dalla sua distruzione totale a causa di un mio errore di configurazione. Ho anche perso i primi tre post perchè le copie di backup non funzionavano&amp;#8230; :&amp;lsquo;(
Beh tutti sbagliano: alla PIXAR hanno distrutto il lavoro di 4 mesi su Toy Story 2 per un comando sbagliato lanciato sui server di storage&amp;#8230;guarda il video!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>