<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on INGE4PRES RATIONAL THOUGHTS</title>
    <link>http://inge.4pr.es/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on INGE4PRES RATIONAL THOUGHTS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 15:27:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://inge.4pr.es/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RESUME</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 15:27:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/resume/</guid>
      <description>Work experiences 9&amp;frasl;2017 - now() » DevOps Engineer @ lastminute group I am contributing mainly to the development of a CI/CD platform to enable developers to test, build and deploy software easily and with confidence; we are part of Platform team and we collaborate with SREs and DBAs to provide developers automated services to consume infrastructure. The end-user platform runs on Kubernetes and we leverage Jenkins and Docker to shorten the feedback loop and continuously improve product quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABOUT</title>
      <link>http://inge.4pr.es/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 15:27:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://inge.4pr.es/about/</guid>
      <description>Bio I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate technology enthusiast, an engineer in love with Computer Science and a part-time musician and writer; I started my career in IT as a sysadmin and became a Go developer in 2013 when approaching distributed systems. I like to study how things work, understand the mechanics of technology products. In my spare time I play drums, bass guitar and acoustic guitar, and sometimes try and write some music; writing small poems is also a passion of mine, as it helps me find a different meaning to things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>